Sebastian Civarolo

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

281.635.5633 scivarolo@gmail.com

sebastiancivarolo.com

github.com/scivarolo

in linkedin.com/in/scivarolo

Experience

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

October 2017-March 2019

Nashville Software School

Intensive full-time, full-stack software development bootcamp focusing on full-stack development fundamentals and problem solving, with the final half of the program executed in a simulated company environment with Scrum methodology completing multiple sprints.

- :: Single-page application development with React and with a focus on modern ES6+ Javascript features, and modular code.
- :: Version controlled individual and group projects with Git and Github.
- :: Project management with issue tickets and Github Projects.
- :: Database planning by building entity relationship diagrams to define relationships with an emphasis on maintaining a flat data structure.
- :: Server-side, test-driven development with Python, Django, and SQL.

GROUP PROJECTS

- :: AgileHR: Employee dashboard for HR departments
 Responsibilities included building out the Models, Views, and Templates in Django/Python
 for managing computers within a company. Create/delete computers, assign computers to
 employees, and keep a history of assignments in the database. Unit tests were written for all
 functionality. Project was conducted as a week-long sprint.
- :: Welcome to Nashville: Find things to do for a day trip to Nashville
 Served as Team Lead on this project. Responsibilities included working with external API to
 fetch restaurant data from Zomato as part of a single page Javascript application.

 » Tools used: Javascript, HTML, CSS, Grunt, ESLint
- :: **Nutshell:** A social dashboard with messaging, events, news, and a to-do list.

 Role included building out the global messaging features that allow users to post a message, and users can edit their own messages. Also built out user relationships in the database and allowed users to "friend" others by clicking on their usernames in the messaging area.

 » Tools used: React, React Router, Reactstrap, Bootstrap, SCSS

GRAPHIC DESIGNER + WEB DEVELOPER

May 2011-September 2018

CORE Design Studio, Houston, TX

Small design/build studio with a collaborative team environment focusing on branding, print, interactive, exhibition, and environmental graphic design that delivers rich experiences. Worked with a client base of mostly non-profits and small businesses, including Inprint Houston, Buffalo Bayou Partnership, Houston Downtown Management District, and Moody Foundation.

- :: Website planning, design, and development for mostly non-profits and small businesses.
- :: Delivered over 15 custom-built, responsive Wordpress sites built with PHP and SCSS. Experience with third-party integrations: Google Maps, Eventbrite, Mailchimp, Events Calendar.
- :: Concept planning, design, production of physical and interactive exhibits for museums, including a touchscreen interactive quiz in Javascript for an educational water museum.
- :: Problem-solving and conceptual design striving for unconventional outcomes that help clients stand out in their field and increase engagement with their audiences.
- :: Branding/Identity design, signage systems and environmental graphic design with a strong emphasis on typography and attention to detail.
- :: Design for print including event collateral, magazines, art books, posters that consistently helped clients increase ticket/table sales for major fundraising events.
- :: Design/production for a quarterly magazine with a distribution of 70,000.
- :: Highly proficient with Adobe software, including Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop, and XD.

About

I worked as a graphic designer for 7 years at a small studio in Houston where web development quickly became one of my main roles. During that time I taught myself everything I knew about web development; mainly HTML, SCSS, and PHP while creating custom Wordpress themes. One of my favorite aspects of web development is that I am always learning something and finding ways to solve new problems. When I moved to Nashville last fall, I knew it was the perfect time to make the natural progression into a full-time career as a software developer.

Projects

BARKEEPER

Barkeeper helps the home bartender keep track of the liquor and other ingredients they have, along with their favorite recipes. Based on the user's inventory, the app tells them what cocktails can be made. Barkeeper is written with React, Bootstrap/Reactstrap and data is stored in a mock API with a flat data structure served by json-server.

github.com/scivarolo/barkeeper

Education

Nashville Software School

Full Stack Software Development, Javascript/Python, 2018–19

University of Houston

BFA Graphic Communications, 2007-11